# Joshua Sobel

# Church Musician, Recording Engineer, Music Educator

121 Cameron Way Cir Winston-Salem, NC 27103 (919) 539-3536

pipeorgan101@gmail.com; sobel.j@artist.uncsa.edu

## **OVERVIEW**

Church musician, recording engineer, and music teacher with more than 11 years of experience on organ and more than 17 years with piano and choir. Professional experience at Methodist, Lutheran, Presbyterian, Baptist, and Episcopal churches. Has won several prizes for performance of hymns and repertoire on organ. Has a special interest and skill set in improvisation. Other skills include computer programming, composing, and aviation.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Centenary United Methodist Church, Winston-Salem - Organ Scholar SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

- Plays a wide range of hymns, liturgy, and solo repertoire for all Sunday church services
- Accompanies the choir for anthems and other works
- Works closely with the Director of Music and other music staff to provide service music

# **Duruflé Academy of Music, Winston-Salem** - Co-Artistic Director

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- As Co-Artistic Director, is involved with planning for the future long-term financial and pedagogical success of the Academy (the goal of which is to transform the approach to music teaching from the elementary level through the conservatory level)
- Has taught or is teaching four beginning piano students
- As a recording engineer, has produced recordings of classical music for the American Guild of Organists, the Oxford University Press, and numerous other organizations and individuals

# Tabernáculo Bautista Agua de Vida, Winston-Salem - Organist/Pianist

OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT

 Plays the hymns, prelude, and postlude for the Sunday afternoon church Services  Spanish-speaking congregation requires great adaptability and flexibility

#### **Augsburg Lutheran Church, Winston-Salem** - Paid Music Intern

SEPTEMBER 2020 - MAY 2022

- Played a wide range of hymns, liturgy, and solo repertoire for church services
- Accompanied the choir for various anthems
- Worked closely with Cantor and other music staff to provide service music

# First Presbyterian Church, Raleigh - Interim Organist

JUNE - AUGUST 2021

- Filled in at short notice for eight weeks for the regular organist
- Played all hymns, liturgy, accompaniments, and other service music for two services each Sunday, as well as weekly choir rehearsals

#### **Various Churches, Raleigh Area** - Substitute Organist

2013 - JANUARY 2021

 I have played for all or parts of services at Edenton Street UMC, Church of the Nativity Episcopal Church, and others, especially in the Raleigh area.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **University of North Carolina School of the Arts** - Bachelor's Degree in Organ Performance

2020 - 2024\* (In Progress)

I am currently a Sophomore at UNCSA studying Organ Performance with Dr. Timothy Olsen.

## Enloe GT/IB Magnet High School - High School Diploma

2016 - 2020

I graduated *Magna Cum Laude* from Enloe, with a 4.12 cumulative weighted GPA. I scored a 35 out of 36 composite on the ACT and a 1520 out of 1600 on the SAT. I took 8 AP courses, including AP Music Theory and AP German, and scored a 4 or 5 on every exam. I was active in the choral program all four years, singing bass, and was also involved with the German Club.

### **Private Organ Lessons**

2013 - 2020

I studied with Josh Dumbleton (former organist at Edenton Street UMC in Raleigh) until 2017, and then with Dr. Mark Andersen, a former student of Marcel Dupré and E. Power Biggs.

#### **Private Piano Lessons**

2006 - 2020

I studied primarily with two different teachers, most recently John Herrmann at the Cary School of Music.

### **AWARDS**

- UNC School of the Arts High School Organ Competition (2020)
  - Hymn Prize
  - o First Prize overall
- National AP Scholar (2020)
- AP Scholar with Distinction (2020)
- AP Scholar with Distinction (2019)
- Greater Columbia AGO Young Organist Competition (2019)
  - o Bach Prize
  - Second Prize Overall
- UNC School of the Arts High School Organ Competition (2019)
  - o Hymn Prize
- Central North Carolina AGO Cooper-Miller Scholarship (2017)
  - o First Prize